{
"quiz2": [
  {
    "id": 1,
    "questionType": "true_false",
    "questionText": "Python got its name from the series Monty Python's Flying Circus?",
    "correctAnswer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"],
    "explination": "Python creator, Guido van Rossum, wanted a short, unique, and slightly mysterious name. Van Rossum decided on Python since he was also reading scripts from Monty Python's Flying Circus"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "questionType": "true_false",
    "questionText": "Is the <ul> HTML tag is used for an Ordered List?",
    "correctAnswer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"],
    "explination": "<ol> stands for Ordered List"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "questionType": "true_false",
    "questionText": "Is the <form> HTML tag used to collect data from users?",
    "correctAnswer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"],
    "explination": "<form> is the HTML tag that allows you to collect data from users"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "questionType": "true_false",
    "questionText": "Are Hard Drives known as the brain of the computer?",
    "correctAnswer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"],
    "explination": "The Central Processing Unit (CPU) is known as the brain of the computer because most of the processing is performed by the CPU."
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "questionType": "true_false",
    "questionText": "Is inheritance deriving new classes from existing classes?",
    "correctAnswer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"],
    "explination": "Inheritance is the concept of OOPs in which new classes are derived from existing classes in order to reuse the properties of classes defined earlier."
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "questionType": "true_false",
    "questionText": "Do static methods belong to the class rather than a specific instance of a class in Java?",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "options": ["true", "false"],
    "explination": "Static methods are methods that belong to the class rather than to any specific instance of the class. Static methods can be called directly on the class itself without needing to create an instance of the class first."  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "questionType": "true_false",
    "questionText": "You can add CSS styles to the head of your HTML document by using the <script> tags.",
    "correctAnswer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"],
    "explination":"CSS is added to HTML by through the <link> tag"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "questionType": "true_false",
    "questionText": "Is the class CSS selector used to specify a group of elements?",
    "correctAnswer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"],
    "explination": "Class selectors are used to specify a group of elements."
  }
  ],
  "quiz1" : [
  {
    "id": 9,
    "questionType": "multiple_choice",
    "questionText": "Which of the following is not a Java feature?",
    "correctAnswer": "Use of Pointers",
    "options":["Use of Pointers", "Dynamic and Extensible", "Object-Oriented", "Portable"],
    "explination": "Pointers is not a Java feature. Java provides an efficient abstraction layer for developing without using a pointer in Java."
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "questionType": "multiple_choice",
    "questionText": "Which of the following properties is used to change the font of text?",
    "correctAnswer": "font-family",
    "options": ["font-size", "text-align", "text-font", "font-family"],
    "explination": "font-size changes the size of your font, text-align affects the position of text, and text-font is not a HTML property"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "questionType": "multiple_choice",
    "questionText": "What does DOM stand for?",
    "correctAnswer": "Document Object Model",
    "options": ["Document-Oriented Memory", "Document Object Memory", "Document Object Model", "None of the Above"],
    "explination": "The Document Object Model (DOM) is a programming interface for web documents. It represents the page so that programs can change the document structure, style, and content."
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "questionType": "multiple_choice",
    "questionText": "Which of the following HTML tags is incorrect?",
    "correctAnswer": "<list>",
    "options": ["<list>", "<textarea>", "<input>", "<select>"],
    "explination": "The correct tag to create a list is <li> not <list>."
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "questionType": "multiple_choice",
    "questionText": "Which of the following is used to allocate and manage resources for a network?",
    "correctAnswer": "Server",
    "options": ["Server", "Bluetooth", "Node", "None of the above"],
    "explination": "Servers allocate and manage resoucres for a network through responding to any requests made to the server. Based on the request the server respondes accordingly to the client."
  },
    {
    "id": 14,
    "questionType": "multiple_choice",
    "questionText": "Which component is used to compile, debug, and execute Java programs?",
    "correctAnswer": "JDK",
    "options": ["JRE", "JVM", "JIT", "JDK"],
    "explination": "JDK is a core component of Java Environment and provides all the tools, executables and binaries required to compile, debug and execute a Java Program."
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "questionType": "multiple_choice",
    "questionText": "What tag is used to create/form a paragraph?",
    "correctAnswer": "<p>",
    "options": ["<br>", "<def>", "<p>", "<hr>"],
    "explination": "<p> creates/forms paragraphs, <br> creates a break, <def> is not a HTML tag and, <hr> defines a shift in topic "
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "questionType": "multiple_choice",
    "questionText": "Which of the following is correct about Javascript?",
    "correctAnswer": "JavaScript is an Object-Based language",
    "options": ["JavaScript is an Object-Oriented language", "JavaScript is an Assembly-language", "JavaScript is a High-Level language", "JavaScript is an Object-Based language"],
    "explination": "Object-based language doesn't support all the features of OOPs like Polymorphism and Inheritance, which JavaScipt does not."  
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "questionType": "multiple_choice",
    "questionText": "What HTML tag is used to embed CSS into the HTML page?",
    "correctAnswer": "<style>",
    "options": ["<style>", "<script>", "<!DOCTYPE html>", "None of the Above"],
    "explination": "<style> tag is used to embed CSS in HTML page, while <script> is used to embed JS in HTML. <!DOCTYPE html> is HTML5 declaration."
  }
]
}

